https://peterntuph.github.io/

# **PROFILE**

I am currently a graduate from Department of Public Health, National Taiwan University. With the goal of bridging the gap between health data researches and interventions, my research interest focus on interplay between causal inference and precision medicine. ■ B05801047@ntu.edu.tw □ +886-956073355

7F., No. 536, Linsen N. Rd., Zhongshan Dist., Taipei City Taiwan (R.O.C.)

## RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

**Taiwan Public Health Association** | Jul.2020 – Present Research Assistant | *Advisor: <u>Tzu-Pin Lu</u>* & <u>Hsien-Ho Lin</u>

 Authorized by Taiwan Centers for Disease Control (CDC) to conduct research on "Post-pandemic lifestyle behavior monitoring"

**Biostatistics & Bioinformatics lab, NTU** | Jun.2019 – Feb.2020 Undergraduate Researcher | *Advisor: Tzu-Pin Lu* 

- Performed 75 % discrimination index (AUCs) by constructing a prognostic model typically for Taiwanese colon cancer patients.
- Poster presentation in 2019 Taiwan Public Health Joint Annual Conference. [Poster Link]
- Won Best Topic Research Poster Award in CPH and granted by College Student Research Scholarship, Ministry of Science and Technology, Taiwan.

# Dept of Medical Research, TVGH | Jun.2019 - Aug.2019

Research Intern | Advisor: <u>Tzu-Hung Hsiao</u>

- Detected susceptibility loci associated with metabolic syndrome to further assist personalized medicine for subjects with abdominal obesity. [Poster Link]
- Under review by 2020 IEEE International Conference on Bioinformatics and Biomedicine (IEEE BIBM 2020)

**Inst of Information Science, Academia Sinica** | Summer.2018

Summer Research Intern and Assistant | Advisor: <u>Da-Wei Wang</u>

 Built Diagnosis Related Groups on Ophthalmology by using machine learning algorithms. [Github Link]

# **EDUCATION**

#### **National Taiwan University**

Bachelor of Science, Public Health

Major: Biostatistics

Infectious Diseases

Cumulative GPA: 3.85/4.3

## LANGUAGE

#### **Advanced Proficiency in English**

GRE (2019,12)

Verbal: 152 (54th Percentile)

Quantitative: 167 (90th Percentile)

Analytical Writing: 3.0

TOEFL (2020,09)

Reading: 29 Speaking: 22 Listening: 28 Writing: 21

Total: 100

Native Proficiency in Mandarin Basic Proficiency in Japanese

## **SKILLS**

#### **Statistical Tools:**

R Language (Proficient) SAS (Basic), SQL(Basic)

#### **Programming:**

Python (Proficient) Markdown (Basic)

# **COMPETITIONS**

## 2018 TMU x MIT (Sana) HIOT Hackathon | Oct.2018

1st Prize with NT\$80,000 (out of 20 teams) [News Link]

- A hackathon organized by Taipei Medical University and MIT Sana Global Team, Boston.
- Proposed an Ultrasound Assisting System for examination of internal hemorrhage with 93% accuracy rate.

## **2018 Hack x Heart** | Sep.2018

#### Top 12 teams (out of 60 teams)

- A hackathon organized by Taiwan Heart Foundation and Ministry of Science and Technology.
- Built an app to increase medication adherence among patient with acute coronary syndrome.
- Won Innovation Award from Xin Chen Medical Research Foundation and School of Pharmacy, NTU.

## **ACTIVITIES**

# **29th Health Services & Dedication Award** | *Volunteer Investigator* **Highest official award for medical personnel in TAIWAN(R.O.C.)**

Aug.2019

- Represented the Legislative Yuan to interview the award nominee.
- Made a presentation in Legislative Yuan for committee to vote for award winner

## **Public Health Student Association** | *Vice president*

Aug.2018 - Aug.2019

- Engaged in curriculum general meeting and uphold student's right to education
- Organized and negotiated with the school authorities for providing more students space

#### **Public Health Summer Service Team** | Leader of Logistics Section

Oct.2018 – Jul.2019

- Raised total \$10,000 USD from Nonprofit Organizations and Foundations.
- Guided 90 students to advocate health promotion in Tainan for a week.

# **AWARDS**

2020	•	Outstanding Graduate Award in College of Public Health, NTU
2020	+	Nominee of Elite Scholarship of Elite-Well Education Foundation
2019	•	Nominee of <b>Dr. KP CHEN Memorial Scholarship</b>

- ✓ Dr. KP CHEN is the father of public health in Taiwan, whose most well-known contribution is to clarify the causality between Blackfoot disease and arsenicosis.
- ✓ Dr. KP CHEN Memorial Scholarship is one of the **Highest award for public health** undergraduates in TAIWAN.

2018 Nominee of **Dr. Jiang Jian Memorial Scholarship** 

2017 • Certificate of Taiwan Medical Information Manager

2017 Certificate of Complete CITI program in Biomedical Human Subject Research